<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000002c2669</Id>
    <Library_Id>c037d0d2-0617-44f3-b846-21dc3d02c4f8</Library_Id>
    <Title>Hard-coded Passwords in Connection Strings</Title>
    <Category>Input and Data Validation</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ASP.NET 4</Technology>
    <Type>Landing Page</Type>
    <DirectLink>Hard-coded Passwords in Connection Strings</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Description==

An applications uses connection strings to specify credentials used to access databases. One way to handle connection strings is to hard-code them into the application. This approach is not secure, because anyone with access to the application code is able to recover these connection strings. Once an attacker has recovered the connection strings, he can use them to access the database(s). To prevent this vulnerability, store connection strings in protected configuration files. To check for this vulnerability, examine all code that uses the database and find where it stored connection strings.

==Impact==

Once the attacker has the database access credentials, he may be able to connect to the database and execute arbitrary queries. The privileges granted to the attacker will be based on the access level of the credentials. Typically, the attacker is then able to retrieve any data in the database, modify any data in the database, delete any data in the database or modify database structure. Having this level of control over the database usually allows the attacker to take full control of the application. If the attacker is able to leverage additional vulnerabilities or the servers are not configured securely, the attacker may also take full control of the application server and the database server.

==Countermeasures==

Store connection strings in protected configuration files:

==Checklists==

Connection strings are stored in protected configuration files:

==Additional Resources==
]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>